Egle StrockyteUX / Product Designer

egle.strockyte@gmail.com 1 (323) 504-1778 | egle.design

PROFILE

I am a digital product designer who enjoys solving complex problems and advocates for data driven and strategic design process. I believe that content precedes design.

I have 6+ years of in-house and agency-side experience, working with clients such as The Economist, McKinsey & Company, City of Santa Monica and Faraday Future.

SKILLS

UX Design and Strategy
Product Design
User Research & Testing
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Content Modeling
UI Design
Creative Concept Development
Typography
HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Publishing (2010) University of the Arts London, LCC

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Media & Culture Studies (2009) Kingston University, London

Fine Arts Diploma (2005) Siauliai Art School, Lithuania

EXPERIENCE

UX Design Director, Edenspiekermann

2016-current

I have created digital products and experiences for brands in automotive, technology, government, publishing and finance. My most recent project includes leading a team of six product designers in creating UI for 10+ unique interactive screens within Faraday Future's electric vehicle.

In my current position, I own and guide my team's design processes, methodologies and activities from concept through o finished product. I enjoy coaching my team through challenges as much as being a hands-on member of the team at all stages of the project.

Digital Designer, The Economist

2015-2016

I helped to create the new digital home of The Economist.
I meaningfully participated in the publication's new website ideating, prototyping, and development process. Proved to thrive in highly iterative environment and succeeded in working with a large globally distributed stakeholders team.

Besides working on economist.com redesign, I was also a principle designer on the project code named CASE.

Throughout this project, I helped to reimagine The Economist's e-commerce journey by redesigning dashboard from which a logged-in user could manage their subscriptions, bookmarks and comments.

Designer, Global Trade Review (GTR)

2012-2015

I planned and led GTR's digital rebrand. Designed and shipped the new responsive company's website alongside the email newsletters and confirmation emails. I played key role in liaison with numerous teams including web developers, editorial and marketing.

Freelance Designer

2011-2012

Worked on various web and print design projects for different clients. Design work mainly included responsive website mock-ups, client reports and presentations, posters and, also, physical product design.